<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>JUMP | Reprex</title>
    <link>https://reprex.nl/tag/jump/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://reprex.nl/tag/jump/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>JUMP</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 13:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://reprex.nl/media/icon_hub9491570ac57158c0eeecc95c95b13e5_20247_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>JUMP</title>
      <link>https://reprex.nl/tag/jump/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jumping Ahead With the Digital Music Observatory</title>
      <link>https://reprex.nl/post/2021-12-02-dmo-jump/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reprex.nl/post/2021-12-02-dmo-jump/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Digital Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt; project spent a year in the JUMP Music Market Accelerator&amp;rsquo;s program. Over the course of 9 months, co-founder Daniel Antal could meet many stakeholders from almost all European countries, meet other new music technology startups and projects, and got mentoring and other professional help to further develop the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Digital Music Observatory is one of the several initiatives to fill the data gaps of the fragmented European music ecosystems.  While most of Europe’s music is available and promoted on data-heavy, AI-driven autonomous platforms like TikTok, Spotify, YouTube, Deezer, music labels, publishers, national export offices are lacking the necessary data solutions to remain competitive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-daniel-is-pitching-for-partnership-with-music-tech-europe-on-linechech-and-finding-a-music-city-that-wants-to-be-the-seat-of-the-future-european-music-observatory-photo-wen-liuhttpwwwfestivalmarscomboard_memberwen-liu&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Daniel is pitching for partnership with Music Tech Europe on Linechech and finding a music city that wants to be the seat of the future European Music Observatory. Photo: [Wen Liu](http://www.festivalmars.com/?board_member=wen-liu/).&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /media/img/blogposts_2021/Daniel_Antal_JUMP_Linecheck_20211124_hubb7c99a8a93f52fd801facb5ffd737fb_546622_3654cf264af950c9a3f1454f74ad2286.webp 400w,
               /media/img/blogposts_2021/Daniel_Antal_JUMP_Linecheck_20211124_hubb7c99a8a93f52fd801facb5ffd737fb_546622_054325de11d3eb6a4b8bcdf23a093705.webp 760w,
               /media/img/blogposts_2021/Daniel_Antal_JUMP_Linecheck_20211124_hubb7c99a8a93f52fd801facb5ffd737fb_546622_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://reprex.nl/media/img/blogposts_2021/Daniel_Antal_JUMP_Linecheck_20211124_hubb7c99a8a93f52fd801facb5ffd737fb_546622_3654cf264af950c9a3f1454f74ad2286.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;557&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      Daniel is pitching for partnership with Music Tech Europe on Linechech and finding a music city that wants to be the seat of the future European Music Observatory. Photo: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.festivalmars.com/?board_member=wen-liu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Wen Liu&lt;/a&gt;.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the recurring themes of 2021 was the notion that the music streaming economy is broken. Several JUMP fellows are working on various projects that aim to fix this, and our Digital Music Observatory has both the data and track record to provide evidence and test ideas about possible solutions – change in pricing, better targeting in export and domestic markets, and checking for algorithmic biases. See what we have done in the field this year in the UK IPO-initiated &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/publication/mce_empirical_streaming_2021/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Music Creators&amp;rsquo; Earning&lt;/a&gt; project; &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/publication/listen_local_2020/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;understanding algorithmic recommendation problems&lt;/a&gt;
with the support of the Slovak Arts Council, and making recommendations about &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/publication/european_visibilitiy_2021/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;better music metadata and copyright regulation&lt;/a&gt; with our research consortium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other very interesting theme of the year was the emergence of new, immersive music tech companies.  We hope that our Digital Music Observatory can grow into a hub for their data needs, too. How is the world of 2.7 billion gamer and music lovers is forming a new market for &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ristband.co/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Ristband&lt;/a&gt;? We would also like to curate data about the healing effects of sound, and work in the future with immersive, functional music providers like &lt;a href=&#34;http://flowerofsound.machinejockey.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Flower of Sound&lt;/a&gt; who place music and sound design into a less stressful, more healthy acoustic environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were often criticized for placing too little emphasis on data visualization. Our next priority is to provide clear, beautiful infographs and charts to all of our datasets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were many professionals who helped us in the JUMP program. We are particularly thankful for Alessanra di Caro (partnership building), Elodie Crouzet (program coordination), &lt;a href=&#34;http://stevefarrismusic.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Steve Farris&lt;/a&gt; (mentoring), &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.holz-consulting.de/en/veronique_friedrich/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Veronique Friedrich&lt;/a&gt; (team building), &lt;a href=&#34;https://speakerscoachbrussels.com/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Thierry Giesler&lt;/a&gt; (improving our pitch) and Anna Zò (&lt;a href=&#34;https://musictecheurope.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Music Tech Europe&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Are you a data user? Give us some feedback! Shall we do some further automatic data enhancements with our datasets? Document with different metadata? Link more information for business, policy, or academic use? Please ive us any &lt;a href=&#34;https://reprex.nl/#contact&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;feedback&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Music Observatory in the Jump European Music Market Accelerator: Meet the 2021 Fellows and their Tutors</title>
      <link>https://reprex.nl/post/2021-03-04-jump-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 15:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reprex.nl/post/2021-03-04-jump-2021/</guid>
      <description>















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /media/img/logos/JUMP_Banner_851x315_hu4cdc4121da73c8e3265aab39577baae8_108992_ccf12428972a82cbd24bafda54692b2c.webp 400w,
               /media/img/logos/JUMP_Banner_851x315_hu4cdc4121da73c8e3265aab39577baae8_108992_f262402b72fb6fe95c1f4bdcb9ce7df4.webp 760w,
               /media/img/logos/JUMP_Banner_851x315_hu4cdc4121da73c8e3265aab39577baae8_108992_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://reprex.nl/media/img/logos/JUMP_Banner_851x315_hu4cdc4121da73c8e3265aab39577baae8_108992_ccf12428972a82cbd24bafda54692b2c.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;281&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the announcement of JUMP, the European Music Market Accelerator, after a careful screening of all applications received, the selection committee composed of all JUMP board members has selected the most promising ideas and projects to be developed together with renowned tutors for this 2021 fellowship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For nine months, the 20 fellows living in many European countries will develop their innovative projects, while receiving a comprehensive 360° training. In addition to specialised workshops by highly qualified experts, each fellow will receive one-on-one tutoring sessions from the most renowned music professionals coming from all over Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 20 selected projects cover a great variety of urgent needs faced within the music sector.
They will:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;help fostering social change with projects focusing on diversity in the industry, more fairness and
transparency as well as raising awareness on timely issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;enhance technological development with projects using blockchain, immersive sound and VR and AR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;build bridges between different key actors of the ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://reprex.nl/documents/JUMP2021_Annoucement_Press_Release_040321.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Download the entire JUMP press release&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reprex&amp;rsquo;s project, the automated &lt;a href=&#34;https://reprex.nl/project/music-observatory/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Demo Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt; will be represented by Daniel Antal, co-founder of Reprex among other building bridges projects. This project offers a different approach to the planned European Music Observatory based on the principles of open collaboration, which allows contributions from small organizations and even individuals, and which provides higher levels of quality in terms of auditability, timeliness, transparency and general ease of use. Our open collaboration approach allows to power trustworthy, ethical AI systems like our &lt;a href=&#34;https://reprex.nl/project/listen-local/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Listen Local&lt;/a&gt; that we started out from Slovakia with the support of the Slovak Arts Council.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-jump-fellows-building-bridges-between-different-key-actors-of-the-ecosystem&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;JUMP fellows building bridges between different key actors of the ecosystem.&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /media/img/reprex/building_bridges_hu047151272ef115b93f0df472b4421474_585232_3c094c224bfc88c7ce7bef53c3d3adf3.webp 400w,
               /media/img/reprex/building_bridges_hu047151272ef115b93f0df472b4421474_585232_200986da45a608039ecc7c8539d60980.webp 760w,
               /media/img/reprex/building_bridges_hu047151272ef115b93f0df472b4421474_585232_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://reprex.nl/media/img/reprex/building_bridges_hu047151272ef115b93f0df472b4421474_585232_3c094c224bfc88c7ce7bef53c3d3adf3.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;392&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      JUMP fellows building bridges between different key actors of the ecosystem.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from our &lt;a href=&#34;https://reprex.nl/project/music-observatory/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Demo Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt; the build bridges section &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jumpmusic.eu/fellow2021/groovly/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Groovly&lt;/a&gt; with Martin Zenzerovich, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jumpmusic.eu/fellow2021/from-play-to-rec/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;From Play To Rec&lt;/a&gt; by Jeremy Dunne, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jumpmusic.eu/fellow2021/hajde-radio/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Hajde Radio&lt;/a&gt; by Thibaut Boudaud, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jumpmusic.eu/fellow2021/lowdee/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;LowDee&lt;/a&gt; by Alex Davidson and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jumpmusic.eu/fellow2021/uno-hu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ONO-HU!&lt;/a&gt; by Gina Akers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Meet all the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jumpmusic.eu/fellows/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;JUMP 2021 Fellows&lt;/a&gt;, including the technology and social change professionals!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reprex is a start-up company based in the Netherlands and the United States that validated its early products in the &lt;a href=&#34;post/2020-09-25-yesdelft-validation/&#34;&gt;Yes!Delft AI+Blockchain Lab&lt;/a&gt; in the Hague. In 2021 we joined the Dutch AI Coalition &amp;ndash; &lt;a href=&#34;post/2021-02-16-nlaic/&#34;&gt;NL AIC&lt;/a&gt; and requested membership in the European AI Alliance. Reprex is committed to applying reproducible in an open collaboration with our business, scientific, policy and civil society partners, and facilitate the use of open data and open-source software. Many fellows in the program are connected to other regions, like North America and Australia &amp;ndash; because music is one of the most globalized industries and forms of art in the world!  Reprex is a startup based in the Netherlands and the United States, and we are very excited to collaborate with our peers in new European territories, and in Canada and Australia.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-hope-to-meet-you-in-these-great-events---maybe-not-only-online&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Hope to meet you in these great events - maybe not only online!&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/2021-03-04-jump-2021/JUMP_events_2021_huc4ee3afec7ca5a36e31b155ecc339395_183968_66c7d8ef3d90da2990059fac82ae686c.webp 400w,
               /post/2021-03-04-jump-2021/JUMP_events_2021_huc4ee3afec7ca5a36e31b155ecc339395_183968_c55ec1e30f1bea8d35c0a5c9bb1a4109.webp 760w,
               /post/2021-03-04-jump-2021/JUMP_events_2021_huc4ee3afec7ca5a36e31b155ecc339395_183968_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://reprex.nl/post/2021-03-04-jump-2021/JUMP_events_2021_huc4ee3afec7ca5a36e31b155ecc339395_183968_66c7d8ef3d90da2990059fac82ae686c.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;307&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      Hope to meet you in these great events - maybe not only online!
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further links:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/fromplaytorec/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;From Play to Rec&lt;/a&gt; on Facebook&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hajde.fr/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;HAJDE&lt;/a&gt; FR/EN&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daniel Antal, co-founder of Reprex Was Selected into the 2021 Fellowship Program of the European Music Market Accelerator</title>
      <link>https://reprex.nl/post/2021-02-22-jump/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 21:23:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reprex.nl/post/2021-02-22-jump/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Daniel Antal, co-founder of Reprex, was selected into 2021 Fellowship program of JUMP, the European Music Market Accelerator. Jump provides a framework for music professionals to develop innovative business models, encouraging the music sector to work on a transnational level.  The European Music Market Accelerator composed of MaMA Festival and Convention, UnConvention, MIL, Athens Music Week, Nouvelle Prague and Linecheck support him in the development of our two, interrelated projects over the next nine months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;a href=&#34;https://reprex.nl/project/music-observatory/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Demo Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt; is a demo version of the European Music Observatory based on open data, open source, automated research in open collaboration with music stakeholders. We hope that we can further develop our business model and find new users, and help the recovery of the festival and live music segment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://reprex.nl/project/listen-local/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Listen Local&lt;/a&gt; is our AI system that validated third party music AI, such as Spotify&amp;rsquo;s or YouTube&amp;rsquo;s recommendation systems, and provides trustworthy, accountable, transparent alternatives for the European music industry. We hope to expand our pilot project from Slovakia to several European countries in 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reprex is a start-up company based in the Netherlands and the United States that validated its early products in the &lt;a href=&#34;post/2020-09-25-yesdelft-validation/&#34;&gt;Yes!Delft AI+Blockchain Lab&lt;/a&gt; in the Hague. In 2021 we joined the Dutch AI Coalition &amp;ndash; &lt;a href=&#34;post/2021-02-16-nlaic/&#34;&gt;NL AIC&lt;/a&gt; and requested membership in the European AI Alliance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reprex is committed to applying reproducible in an open collaboration with our business, scientific, policy and civil society partners, and facilitate the use of open data and open-source software.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
