<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ccsi | Reprex</title>
    <link>https://reprex.nl/tag/ccsi/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://reprex.nl/tag/ccsi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>ccsi</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2021 16:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://reprex.nl/media/icon_hub9491570ac57158c0eeecc95c95b13e5_20247_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>ccsi</title>
      <link>https://reprex.nl/tag/ccsi/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reprex Joins RECREO Research Consortium To Develop Innovation Indicators</title>
      <link>https://reprex.nl/post/2021-10-06-recreo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2021 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reprex.nl/post/2021-10-06-recreo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.santannapisa.it/it&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Scuola Superiore di Studi Universitari e di Perfezionamento Sant’Anna&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unitn.it/en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Università degli Studi di Trento&lt;/a&gt; (Italy); &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.create.ac.uk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;University of Glasgow&lt;/a&gt; (United Kingdom); &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ivir.nl/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Universiteit van Amsterdam&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://pro.europeana.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Stichting Europeana&lt;/a&gt; from the	Netherlands; the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.maynoothuniversity.ie/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;National University of Ireland Maynooth&lt;/a&gt;	(Ireland); &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ut.ee/en/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Tartu Ulikool&lt;/a&gt;	(Estonia); &lt;a href=&#34;https://u-szeged.hu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Szegedi Tudományegyetem&lt;/a&gt; (Hungary); &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.santamarialareal.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Fundacion Santa Maria La Real del Patrimonio Historico&lt;/a&gt; from Spain; the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kuleuven.be/kuleuven/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Katholieke Universiteit Leuven&lt;/a&gt;,	(Belgium); &lt;a href=&#34;https://cultureactioneurope.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Culture Action Europe AISBL&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ideaconsult.be/en/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;IDEA Strategische Economische Consulting&lt;/a&gt; 	(Belgium) and &lt;a href=&#34;https://reprex.nl/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Reprex&lt;/a&gt; created the&lt;code&gt;REshaping CCSI REsearch: Open data, policy analysis and methods for evidence-based decision-making consortium&lt;/code&gt; consortium, which will mainly develop new policy evidence in the field of innovation and inclusiveness for the creative and cultural sectors, industries. The Consortium applies for a Horizon Europe grant with the &lt;code&gt;HORIZON-CL2-2021-HERITAGE-01-03&lt;/code&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://ec.europa.eu/info/funding-tenders/opportunities/portal/screen/opportunities/topic-details/horizon-cl2-2021-heritage-01-03&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Cultural and creative industries as a driver of innovation and competitiveness&lt;/a&gt; call of the European Commission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Policymakers face challenges when trying to implement a strict evidence-based approach to decision-making in the field of cultural and creative sectors and industries (CCSI). This is mostly due to four phenomena:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Evidence dissonances in mapping, measuring and analysis of key indicators&lt;/code&gt;, which lead to improper generalizations and gaps in decisionmakers’ knowledge and stakeholders’ awareness&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Fragmentation of hubs of production and concentration of platforms&lt;/code&gt;, which create statistical biases and have features that hardly fit with traditional impact assessment methods;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Datafication&lt;/code&gt;, which is revolutionizing CCSI but remains difficult to investigate, thus broadening knowledge gaps; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Stakeholders’ fragmentation and conflicting interests&lt;/code&gt;, which hinders their engagement, awareness-raising and uptake of policy inputs.With its cross-disciplinary consortium of academics, practitioners and a strong network of stakeholders, engaged via participatory research strategies, RECREO will help policymakers and stakeholders tackling such challenges, by generating new knowledge and methods to fill in knowledge and awareness gaps. RECREO will achieve this goal through four actions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, it will generate a wide array of horizontal and sector-specific datasets, made openly accessible via the &lt;a href=&#34;https://reprex.nl/project/ccsi-data-observatory/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CCSI Data Observatory&lt;/a&gt; and the Evidence Synthesis Platform. Second, it will offer an unprecedented EU and comparative mapping and impact assessment of key regulatory and policy measures relevant for CCSI, made available on the Law and Policy Observatory. Third, it will develop innovative methods to measure and assess CCSI innovation, competitiveness and spill-over effects, emphasizing inclusiveness, diversity and sustainability. Last, it will offer policy recommendations and best practices aimed at supporting the sustainable growth and competitiveness of culturally diverse CCSI, and their cross-fertilization with cultural heritage promotion and preservation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CCSI Data Observatory</title>
      <link>https://reprex.nl/post/2021-10-05-ccsi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reprex.nl/post/2021-10-05-ccsi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The creative and cultural sectors and industries are mainly made of networks of freelancers and microenterprises, with very few medium-sized companies. Their economic performance, problems, and innovation capacities hidden. Our open collaboration to create this data observatory is committed to change this. Relying on modern data science, the re-use of open governmental data, open science data, and novel harmonized data collection we aim to fill in the gaps left in the official statistics of the European Union.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe that introducing Open Policy Analysis standards with open data, open-source software and research automation can help better understanding how creative people and their enterprises and institutions add value to the European economy, how they create jobs, innovate, and increase the well-being of a diverse European society. Our collaboration is open for individuals, citizens scientists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new observatory can be reached on &lt;a href=&#34;https://ccsi.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ccsi.dataobservatory.eu&lt;/a&gt; and will be institutionally hosted by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ivir.nl/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;IViR&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;em&gt;Institute for Information Law&lt;/em&gt; of the University of Amsterdam, where Reprex’s co-founder, Daniel Antal will coordinate the development of this new, open scientific tool. Reprex will continue to develop the working model of the data observatory and continue to build open source software tools within the &lt;a href=&#34;http://ropengov.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;rOpenGov community&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ropengov.r-universe.dev/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;R-Universe&lt;/a&gt; initative of ROpenSci.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.santannapisa.it/it&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Scuola Superiore di Studi Universitari e di Perfezionamento Sant’Anna&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unitn.it/en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Università degli Studi di Trento&lt;/a&gt; (Italy); &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.create.ac.uk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;University of Glasgow&lt;/a&gt; (United Kingdom); &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ivir.nl/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Universiteit van Amsterdam&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://pro.europeana.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Stichting Europeana&lt;/a&gt; from the	Netherlands; the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.maynoothuniversity.ie/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;National University of Ireland Maynooth&lt;/a&gt;	(Ireland); &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ut.ee/en/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Tartu Ulikool&lt;/a&gt;	(Estonia); &lt;a href=&#34;https://u-szeged.hu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Szegedi Tudományegyetem&lt;/a&gt; (Hungary); &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.santamarialareal.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Fundacion Santa Maria La Real del Patrimonio Historico&lt;/a&gt; from Spain; the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kuleuven.be/kuleuven/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Katholieke Universiteit Leuven&lt;/a&gt;,	(Belgium); &lt;a href=&#34;https://cultureactioneurope.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Culture Action Europe AISBL&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ideaconsult.be/en/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;IDEA Strategische Economische Consulting&lt;/a&gt; 	(Belgium) and Reprex created the the &lt;code&gt;RECREO&lt;/code&gt; consortium, which will mainly develop new policy evidence in the field of innovation and inclusiveness for the creative and cultural sectors, industries. The Consortium applies for a Horizon Europe grant with the &lt;code&gt;HORIZON-CL2-2021-HERITAGE-01-03&lt;/code&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://ec.europa.eu/info/funding-tenders/opportunities/portal/screen/opportunities/topic-details/horizon-cl2-2021-heritage-01-03&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Cultural and creative industries as a driver of innovation and competitiveness&lt;/a&gt; call of the European Commission.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
