<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Recent &amp; Upcoming Talks | Reprex</title>
    <link>https://reprex.nl/event/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://reprex.nl/event/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Recent &amp; Upcoming Talks</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 09:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://reprex.nl/media/icon_hub9491570ac57158c0eeecc95c95b13e5_20247_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Recent &amp; Upcoming Talks</title>
      <link>https://reprex.nl/event/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reprex Nominated for The Hague Innovators Award</title>
      <link>https://reprex.nl/talk/reprex-nominated-for-the-hague-innovators-award/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reprex.nl/talk/reprex-nominated-for-the-hague-innovators-award/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Reprex is a finalist for The Hague Innovators Award 2022, and the prize of the audience, in the startup category with our respectable competitors, Sibö, WECO, STHRIVE and ECOBLOQ.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The transition towards a sustainable and inclusive economy depends on collaboration. That is why we are bringing together startups, scale-ups, investors, policymakers, and other impact makers from around the world in The Hague for the 7th edition of ImpactFest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.impactcity.nl/en/service/the-hague-innovators-challenge/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Hague Innovators Challenge&lt;/a&gt;, the municipality of The Hague challenges startups, scale-ups, and students to present their innovative ideas for global issues, as described in the UN Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The nominees receive a substantive program aimed at further development and the growth of the plan or organization. At the end of the substantive program, all nominees submit a definitive action plan and this is pitched to a professional jury. The jury chooses one winner per category.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Data for All - Building Collaborative Data Observatories</title>
      <link>https://reprex.nl/talk/big-data-for-all-building-collaborative-data-observatories/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reprex.nl/talk/big-data-for-all-building-collaborative-data-observatories/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Daniel Antal, Reprex’s founder will talk in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ehvinnovationcafe.org/past-events/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Eindhoven Innovation Café&lt;/a&gt;. You can rewatch some former talks on their website.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ImpactCity Startup Support XL</title>
      <link>https://reprex.nl/talk/impactcity-startup-support-xl/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reprex.nl/talk/impactcity-startup-support-xl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!---
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://reprex.nl/documents/Reprex-ImpactCity-2022.pdf&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;Do something&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

---&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reprex is a research automation company with an international team and clientele. We validated our product/market fit in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:4321/post/2020-09-25-yesdelft-validation/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Yes!Delft AI+Blockchain Lab&lt;/a&gt; in 2020 and started to build research automation tools for complex data problems with a fast-growing user base and a very high-level international recognition in the EU and the UK. Our dual product offers us to participate in large data platform PPP projects and find growth opportunities in building data-driven commercial applications simultaneously. We want to scale up our operations in the Hague, where we are registered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Reprex is a finalist for &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.impactcity.nl/en/service/the-hague-innovators-challenge/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Hague Innovators Challenge&lt;/a&gt; and the prize of the audience.&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://reprex.nl/documents/Reprex-ImpactCity-2022.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Download this information in 1 page.&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://reprex.nl/slides/reprex-impactcity/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Check out our pitch deck&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-our-platform-solution-is-a-modernized-future-proof-web-30-version-of-the-data-observatories-of-the-eu-un-and-oecd&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Our platform solution is a modernized, future-proof, web 3.0 version of the data observatories of the EU, UN, and OECD.&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /media/img/observatory_screenshots/observatory_collage_16x9_800_hu47f74f5cdae63c7248c2367b9d148671_353025_0079ea9844f6c5e52b52fd0e627467a2.webp 400w,
               /media/img/observatory_screenshots/observatory_collage_16x9_800_hu47f74f5cdae63c7248c2367b9d148671_353025_ecd6d08ba5e9bac19c8173546f036651.webp 760w,
               /media/img/observatory_screenshots/observatory_collage_16x9_800_hu47f74f5cdae63c7248c2367b9d148671_353025_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://reprex.nl/media/img/observatory_screenshots/observatory_collage_16x9_800_hu47f74f5cdae63c7248c2367b9d148671_353025_0079ea9844f6c5e52b52fd0e627467a2.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;428&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      Our platform solution is a modernized, future-proof, web 3.0 version of the data observatories of the EU, UN, and OECD.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About 60 large data observatories worldwide serve numerous consultancies, universities, NGOs, and other knowledge-based organizations with consistent information collection and processing. We want to power at least 10% of these global knowledge infrastructures in 5 years because we think our technology is superior to almost all of them. By providing essential services to them, we get access to the data ecosystems of prime governmental, academic, and large corporate users.
Our central position in one mature and four emerging observatories allows us to provide shared services to for-profit and non-profit organizations that do not have a data science/engineering team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also have a compelling proposition to an organization that had built large database systems that became quickly obsolete: we offer them an alternative to rigid relational databases. We provide these organizations with competitive data acquisition, processing, knowledge management, and documentation services, which enables even very small commercial or civil society partners to deploy (ethical) AI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-after-winning-a-very-competitive-horizon-europe-research-and-innovation-tender-we-are-upgrading-our-digital-music-observatoryhttpsmusicdataobservatoryeu-to-be-an-officially-recognized-shared-data-resource-of-the-european-music-sector&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;After winning a very competitive Horizon Europe Research and Innovation tender, we are upgrading our [Digital Music Observatory](https://music.dataobservatory.eu/) to be an officially recognized, shared data resource of the European music sector.&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /media/img/screenshots/dmo_opening_page_20220920_16x9_hu344f27424eb62a848e32b408f44fd3a5_269226_07fc150ebe2040ed28d46029cbb43f2d.webp 400w,
               /media/img/screenshots/dmo_opening_page_20220920_16x9_hu344f27424eb62a848e32b408f44fd3a5_269226_8ee27c6b7fa6d4f566b021ecccd05d1a.webp 760w,
               /media/img/screenshots/dmo_opening_page_20220920_16x9_hu344f27424eb62a848e32b408f44fd3a5_269226_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://reprex.nl/media/img/screenshots/dmo_opening_page_20220920_16x9_hu344f27424eb62a848e32b408f44fd3a5_269226_07fc150ebe2040ed28d46029cbb43f2d.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;396&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      After winning a very competitive Horizon Europe Research and Innovation tender, we are upgrading our &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Digital Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt; to be an officially recognized, shared data resource of the European music sector.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our observatories are PPP data ecosystems that create many jobs, not only in our startup but in their city ecosystems, too.  As a permanent EU organization similar to the European Audiovisual Observatory, it can create up to 35 crucial knowledge jobs in Strasbourg. We want to join forces with the Hague, the Europeana (the EU cultural heritage body in the Hague), the PAARD, and other actors to make the permanent place of the European Music Observatory in the Hague. This work connects mainly to SGD Goal 5 (detecting algorithmic biases against womxn) and SDG Goal 8 (decent work for creative freelancers and protecting their income from global data monopolies).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would also like to attract at least one more European or global observatory to the city. Our beachhead/flagship ecosystem is in music. We started expanding towards the related film, gaming, fashion, architecture, and other copyright-based industries. We also discovered function-specific uses that allowed us to go into commercially far more lucrative directions: we started building a computational antitrust and an environmental and social reporting supporting green observatory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-we-think-that-our-software-as-service-components-for-connected-financial-sustainability-reporting-fueled-by-our-emerging-computational-antitrusthttpscompetitiondataobservatoryeu-and-green-deal-data-observatorieshttpsgreendealdataobservatoryeu-provide-an-entry-into-the-4-billion-euro-market-of-connecting-financial-and-sustainability-reporting-and-can-make-a-very-significant-impact-related-to-the-sdg-goals-12-responsible-consumption-and-goals-13-climate-change&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;We think that our software-as-service components for connected financial-sustainability reporting, fueled by our emerging [Computational Antitrust](https://competition.dataobservatory.eu/) and [Green Deal Data Observatories](https://greendeal.dataobservatory.eu/), provide an entry into the 4-billion-euro market of connecting financial and sustainability reporting and can make a very significant impact related to the SDG Goals 12 (responsible consumption) and Goals 13 (climate change). &#34; srcset=&#34;
               /media/img/eviota/Eviota_EFRAG_requirements_hu3389cdfb13c4fd9efff0a2d75d3bc17d_231927_ba07bcb2cab6a041c8fa07a66f44c402.webp 400w,
               /media/img/eviota/Eviota_EFRAG_requirements_hu3389cdfb13c4fd9efff0a2d75d3bc17d_231927_4a745162ba521fe0933b7f1e31de6032.webp 760w,
               /media/img/eviota/Eviota_EFRAG_requirements_hu3389cdfb13c4fd9efff0a2d75d3bc17d_231927_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://reprex.nl/media/img/eviota/Eviota_EFRAG_requirements_hu3389cdfb13c4fd9efff0a2d75d3bc17d_231927_ba07bcb2cab6a041c8fa07a66f44c402.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;428&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      We think that our software-as-service components for connected financial-sustainability reporting, fueled by our emerging &lt;a href=&#34;https://competition.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Computational Antitrust&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://greendeal.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Green Deal Data Observatories&lt;/a&gt;, provide an entry into the 4-billion-euro market of connecting financial and sustainability reporting and can make a very significant impact related to the SDG Goals 12 (responsible consumption) and Goals 13 (climate change).
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The banking, financial and antitrust regulators are forcing first the 49,000 large EU companies by 2024, then the SMEs and e-commerce platforms to provide auditable accounts of their environmental and social impacts in their entire value chains.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Listen Local Utrecht</title>
      <link>https://reprex.nl/talk/listen-local-utrecht/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reprex.nl/talk/listen-local-utrecht/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our Listen Local project aims to develop tools that can be used by independent labels and self-releasing artists to make sure that their music finds relevant audiences in their scene, in their geographical environment and abroad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    The purpose of the meetup is to provide an informal setting to get to know each other, or exchange ideas and get into action. RSV on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eventbrite.com/manage/events/411140571517/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Eventbrite&lt;/a&gt;, on &lt;a href=&#34;https://keybase.io/team/reprexcommunity&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Keybase&lt;/a&gt; or via the &lt;a href=&#34;https://reprex.nl/#contact&#34;&gt;contact form&lt;/a&gt;.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are working with leading EU and UK universities and industry associations to find out why sometimes Utrecht-based music is not recommended to people in Utrecht on streaming platforms? Or how we could build applications that bring the local music ecosystem into the attention of visitors, tourists?  Or how we could build games or educational applications that help local youth, pupils, students, educators, with artists in their town, and expand their music discovery to the province, their country, neighboring countries, instead of only recommending a few artists from New York, London, Rio de Janeiro or Seoul.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Map shows what rock bands mean when they announce a &amp;quot;World tour&amp;quot;. Really clever idea for a map I think! Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/ACjTZgdGJ7&#34;&gt;https://t.co/ACjTZgdGJ7&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/3LnVnlM2PS&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/3LnVnlM2PS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Simon Kuestenmacher (@simongerman600) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/simongerman600/status/1219730171407872001?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;January 21, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the help of MusicAIRE and Horizon Europe, Europe’s premiere research and innovation grant, we are building open source tools to help to solve these problems, or allow other developers to build new applications and games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reprex is a member of the Dutch AI Coalition&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://nlaic.com/en/sectors/culture/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Culture and Media Working Group&lt;/a&gt;. The Dutch AI Coalition wants to make sure that algorithms work for all. This informal event will take place after the annual gathering of the working group from 9.00-18.00, with working groups members optional visit the Culture AI Lab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details class=&#34;spoiler &#34;  id=&#34;spoiler-2&#34;&gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;Interested in the Dutch AI Coalition event?&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If you are interested in those professional events, get in touch with us on  &lt;a href=&#34;https://keybase.io/team/reprexcommunity&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Keybase&lt;/a&gt; or via the &lt;a href=&#34;https://reprex.nl/#contact&#34;&gt;contact form&lt;/a&gt;.
{{/spoiler}}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dutch AI Coalition Working Group Culture and Media</title>
      <link>https://reprex.nl/talk/dutch-ai-coalition-working-group-culture-and-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reprex.nl/talk/dutch-ai-coalition-working-group-culture-and-media/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Reprex is presenting its &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Digital Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://ccsi.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Cultural Creative Sectors Industries Data Observatory&lt;/a&gt; as platforms for developing and evaluating trustworthy AI in the cultural domains. We hope to find new partners within the NLAIC community to join our open, collaborative projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more about the Dutch AI Coalition&amp;rsquo;s Cultur and Media Working Group (in Dutch:)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://player.vimeo.com/video/649975584&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;vimeo video&#34; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Listen Local Vilnius</title>
      <link>https://reprex.nl/talk/listen-local-vilnius/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reprex.nl/talk/listen-local-vilnius/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our Listen Local project aims to develop tools that can be used by independent labels and self-releasing artists to make sure that their music finds relevant audiences in their scene, in their geographical environment and abroad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    The purpose of the meetup is to provide an informal setting to get to know each other, or exchange ideas and get into action. RSV on &lt;a href=&#34;https://keybase.io/team/reprexcommunity&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Keybase&lt;/a&gt; or via the &lt;a href=&#34;https://reprex.nl/#contact&#34;&gt;contact form&lt;/a&gt;.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are working with leading EU and UK universities and industry associations to find out why sometimes Utrecht-based music is not recommended to people in Utrecht on streaming platforms? Or how we could build applications that bring the local music ecosystem into the attention of visitors, tourists?  Or how we could build games or educational applications that help local youth, pupils, students, educators, with artists in their town, and expand their music discovery to the province, their country, neighboring countries, instead of only recommending a few artists from New York, London, Rio de Janeiro or Seoul.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Map shows what rock bands mean when they announce a &amp;quot;World tour&amp;quot;. Really clever idea for a map I think! Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/ACjTZgdGJ7&#34;&gt;https://t.co/ACjTZgdGJ7&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/3LnVnlM2PS&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/3LnVnlM2PS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Simon Kuestenmacher (@simongerman600) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/simongerman600/status/1219730171407872001?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;January 21, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the help of MusicAIRE and Horizon Europe, Europe’s premiere research and innovation grant, we are building open source tools to help to solve these problems, or allow other developers to build new applications and games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reprex is a member of the Dutch AI Coalition&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://nlaic.com/en/sectors/culture/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Culture and Media Working Group&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details class=&#34;spoiler &#34;  id=&#34;spoiler-2&#34;&gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;Interested in the Dutch AI Coalition event?&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If you are interested in those professional events, get in touch with us on  &lt;a href=&#34;https://keybase.io/team/reprexcommunity&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Keybase&lt;/a&gt; or via the &lt;a href=&#34;https://reprex.nl/#contact&#34;&gt;contact form&lt;/a&gt;.
{{/spoiler}}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Listen Local</title>
      <link>https://reprex.nl/talk/listen-local/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reprex.nl/talk/listen-local/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Daniel Antal will introduce &lt;code&gt;Listen Local Lithuania&lt;/code&gt;, a new offspring of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Digital Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt;’s trustworthy AI program, &lt;a href=&#34;http://listen-local.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Listen Local&lt;/a&gt;, and show what artists, managers, labels, and cultural policymakers can do to ideas about balancing the post-Covid revenues with increased sales on global platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on our experience in Slovakia (see: &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/publication/listen_local_2020/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Feasibility Study On Promoting Slovak Music In Slovakia &amp;amp; Abroad&lt;/a&gt;), and new data from Lithuania and Ukraine we show what data management problems make the Lithuanian music invisible for the AI algorithms of YouTube, Spotify and other platforms; how artists from Vilnius or Kaunas can find their new release on &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2020-10-24-forgetify_pop_october/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Forgetify&lt;/a&gt;, and app that plays songs that were never played. We show why music revenues decreased in the past years for independent and small country catalogues, and we give practical advice on increasing the value and visibility of the Lithuanian music repertoire. We show an open, data federation model to connect the Lithuanian national library the system of collective management, distributors, and small data of artists and labels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;prepare-your-questions&#34;&gt;Prepare your questions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you want to know why your music is not recommended by streaming platforms?  Are you interested in finding new Lithuanian music that fits into your radio or festival programming but your are stuck? You can &lt;a href=&#34;https://reprex.nl/#contact&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;send questions&lt;/a&gt; prior to the conference to the speaker, &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/author/daniel-antal/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Daniel Antal&lt;/a&gt;, and we&amp;rsquo;ll address your problem with examples in the talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;opt-in&#34;&gt;Opt-in&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can opt-in into our database before or during the conference, and we will give you tailored analysis about your data quality, and your opportunities to place your music to new audiences in Lithuania and abroad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;venue&#34;&gt;Venue&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk will be in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://wnim.lt/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;what&amp;rsquo;s next in music&lt;/a&gt; conference  or follow them on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/WhatsNextInMusic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;. Participation is free but requires registration.  (We will post shortly more details on this.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The time set for the talk is &lt;code&gt;EEST Vilnius time&lt;/code&gt; (GMT+02.00).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;not-available&#34;&gt;Not available?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can meet the project&amp;rsquo;s manager and the speaker on 10 September in Kaunas, at the closing event of &lt;a href=&#34;https://wnim.lt/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;what&amp;rsquo;s next in music&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Listen Local Lithuania&lt;/code&gt; is supported by the European Union&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://musicaire.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;MusicAIRE&lt;/a&gt;, an EU-funded project that aims to provide tailored-made instruments for the sector and contribute to a green, digital, just, and resilient recovery of the music ecosystem. It is managed by MXF in collaboration with Music Export Ukraine and Reprex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/author/mxf-muzikos-eksporto-fondas/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;MXF&lt;/a&gt; and the outcomes of the &lt;code&gt;Listen Local Lithuania&lt;/code&gt; will participate in the OpenMusE project, an international research and innovation project with prestigious universities, music industry stakeholders, collective management organizations, and innovative SMEs to design tools that promote the diversity of music on global platforms, increase the revenues and decrease the data costs of music organizations, provide cultural policymakers with the Open Policy Analysis framework the first time in Europe. This open collaboration project funded for 2023-2025 is open for small and large music organizations, collective management organizations, libraries, and cultural policymakers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Music Observatory on the MaMA Convention 2021</title>
      <link>https://reprex.nl/talk/digital-music-observatory-on-the-mama-convention-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reprex.nl/talk/digital-music-observatory-on-the-mama-convention-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Currently more than half of the global music sales are made by autonomous AI systems owned by Google, Apple, or Spotify. These data monopolies are getting rich, because they reap the profit from music businesses with an average employee count of 1.8 Europe. European music businesses are easy to exploit with armies of data engineers and data scientists because they do not have a single data scientist or even an IT function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Artists in the UK had a difficulty explaining in Westminster how they are losing out in streaming– so we have created a streaming price index, like the Dow Jones, if you like, that explains the economic factors of the devaluation of music in the last 5 years in 20 countries. (See &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/publication/mce_empirical_streaming_2021/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;our report&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Music organizations in Slovakia and Hungary were frustrated that their politicians and journalists believed music to be taxpayer funded, so we showed with data that they contribute more proportionally to the national budget than car manufacturers, the darling of local politicians (See our reports in &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/publication/hungary_music_industry_2014/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Hungary&lt;/a&gt; (recast several times) and in &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/publication/slovak_music_industry_2019/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Slovakia&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We successfully challenged with data restaurant associations, hotel chains, telecom corporations and broadcasters who wanted to bring music prices down in court and via lobbying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The music industry has envied the television and film industry which has a single go-to-point for data when it needs them, the European Audiovisual Observatory. It started lobbying for a publicly financed music observatory. But we did not wait. The music industry has a tragic track record of failed centralized international data projects. We built Reprex out of a 12-country, decentralized music project. We learned how to utilize hidden, but already existing data and research funds well, and how to manage the data governance among the poisonous conflicts of interests between rich and poor countries, authors vs producers, producer’s vs performers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Digital Music Observatory&lt;/a&gt; is not theoretical, it is practical, because it is built around real-life court cases, damage claims, lobbying and PR arguments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Digital Music Observatory is comprehensive – it contains more than a thousand indicators from all European countries. We have enough data to test the biases of the Spotify or the YouTube algorithm – you would be surprised what the data tells us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has data available much sooner, in much higher quality and in a more practical format than in the Audiovisual one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;presentation-slides&#34;&gt;Presentation Slides&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see the presentation slides &lt;a href=&#34;https://reprex.nl/slides/mama_2021/#/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crunchconf: Open Data, New Gold Without the Rush</title>
      <link>https://reprex.nl/talk/crunchconf-open-data-new-gold-without-the-rush/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 10:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reprex.nl/talk/crunchconf-open-data-new-gold-without-the-rush/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every year, the EU announces that billions and billions of data are now “open” again, but this is not gold. At least not in the form of nicely minted gold coins, but in gold dust and nuggets found in the muddy banks of chilly rivers. There is no rush for it, because panning out its value requires a lot of hours of hard work. Our goal is to automate this work to make open data usable at scale, even in trustworthy AI solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In his presentation, Daniel compared the current state of open data (including governmental open data and scientific open data) to a thrift store.  You can often find bargains, or historical data that would be impossible to source from data vendors, but on a strictly as-is basis, without a catalogue, service, or guarantee. Therefore, working with open data requires a careful reprocessing, validation, and in many cases, frequent re-validation. Open data is often over-estimated: it is never a finished product, often it cannot even be downloaded, therefore it requires further investment to make it valuable. However, because most open data arrives from the governmental sector, you can tap into information sources where no market alternative exists.  Open data in some cases may be a cheaper substitute to market vendors, but often it is an exclusive source of information that do not have any market vendors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-sisyphus-was-punished-by-being-forced-to-roll-an-immense-boulder-up-a-hill-only-for-it-to-roll-down-every-time-it-neared-the-top-repeating-this-action-for-eternity--this-is-the-price-that-project-managers-and-analysts-pay-for-the-inadequate-documentation-of-their-data-assets&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Sisyphus was punished by being forced to roll an immense boulder up a hill only for it to roll down every time it neared the top, repeating this action for eternity.  This is the price that project managers and analysts pay for the inadequate documentation of their data assets.&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /media/img/blogposts_2021/Sisyphus_Bodleian_Library_hu99f0c1d6c82963b9538437670b4d339d_1662894_cd48a6c374c9ff68a08abe79a6abf2f4.webp 400w,
               /media/img/blogposts_2021/Sisyphus_Bodleian_Library_hu99f0c1d6c82963b9538437670b4d339d_1662894_a6eb1b13ff33a5c73aba34550964ff52.webp 760w,
               /media/img/blogposts_2021/Sisyphus_Bodleian_Library_hu99f0c1d6c82963b9538437670b4d339d_1662894_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://reprex.nl/media/img/blogposts_2021/Sisyphus_Bodleian_Library_hu99f0c1d6c82963b9538437670b4d339d_1662894_cd48a6c374c9ff68a08abe79a6abf2f4.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;507&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      Sisyphus was punished by being forced to roll an immense boulder up a hill only for it to roll down every time it neared the top, repeating this action for eternity.  This is the price that project managers and analysts pay for the inadequate documentation of their data assets.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The practices related to the exploitation of open data are not only relevant in an open data context: these are good data ingestion and procurement practices for &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; third party data, and in large organizations, for any cross-departmental data. (See the blogpost: &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-07-08-data-sisyphus/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Data Sisyphus&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Case Study:  &lt;a href=&#34;https://greendeal.dataobservatory.eu/post/2021-04-23-belgium-flood-insurance/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Belgian Drought/Flood Risk Awareness, Financial Capacity &amp;amp; Hydrology&lt;/a&gt; a complex integration of various open data sources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the second part of the presentation, Daniel talked about our modern data observatory concept.  We have reviewed about 80 functioning and already defunct international data collection programs.  Data observatories, like Copernicus’ Observatory, are permanent infrastructure to record various domain-specific data, such as alternative fuel information, information on homelessness, or on the European music business.  In our assessment, most of the EU, OECD, UNESCO recognized or endorsed observatories use obsolete technology and do not rely on the new achievements of data science. Reprex, our start-up offers an open source, open data based alternative solution to build largely automated data observatories.  We believe that human judgement is needed in data curation, but processing, documentation and validation is best done by computers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Case Study: &lt;a href=&#34;https://greendeal.dataobservatory.eu/post/2021-03-06-regions-climate/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Reprocessing geographical information with administrative boundary changes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At last, he presented a few development directions with our open-source software, mentioning our work withing the rOpenGov community. This part of the presentation was originally meant to open the way for a half-day open data workshop, but due to the current pandemic situation, the physical part of the conference and the workshops were not held.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The presentation largely included the topics of our Data &amp;amp; Lyrics blogpost: &lt;a href=&#34;https://greendeal.dataobservatory.eu/post/2021-06-18-gold-without-rush/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Open Data&amp;mdash;The New Gold Without the Rush&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;presentation-slides&#34;&gt;Presentation Slides&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See the presentation slides &lt;a href=&#34;https://reprex.nl/slides/crunchconf_2021/#/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reprex Open Data Day 2021</title>
      <link>https://reprex.nl/talk/reprex-open-data-day-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 15:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reprex.nl/talk/reprex-open-data-day-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://opendataday.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Open Data Day&lt;/a&gt;  is an annual celebration of open data all over the world. It is an opportunity to show the benefits of open data and encourage the adoption of open data policies in government, business, and civil society. Reprex is a start-up that utilizes open data with open-source reproducible research: please challenge us with your data requests and participate in our web events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;Reprex Open Data Day 2021&lt;/code&gt; will be two informal conversations based on a series of run up introductory blogposts centered around two themes. Because important guests became ill in the last days, we are going to consolidate the two talks into one with less structure.  We want to create an informal, inclusive, collaborative online event on International Open Data Day 2021. Please, grab a tea, coffee, or even a beer, and join us for an informal conversation. We hope that we will finish the afternoon with ideas on new, open-data driven collaborations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;9.30 EST / 15.30 CET&lt;/code&gt;:  &lt;strong&gt;Open collaboration in business, policy and science.&lt;/strong&gt;   Creating evidence-based policy, business strategy or scientific research with small contributions with independent components with incentives.  Short introduction with examples:  joining environmental sensory data and public opinion data on maps; creating harmonized datasets across the Arab world.  Survey harmonization, mapping, data products.  &lt;strong&gt;Scaling up open collaboration: making small organizations competitive with big tech in the big data era.&lt;/strong&gt;  Data sharing, data pooling, data altruism and observatories. The new European trustworthy AI and data governance agenda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can &lt;a href=&#34;https://reprex.nl/presentations/reprex_open_data_day_2021.html#/reprex&#34;&gt;click through&lt;/a&gt; a short presentation to familiarize yourself with our topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See you &lt;a href=&#34;https://meet.jit.si/ReprexOpenDataDay2021&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Case studies:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are connecting raw survey data about Climate Awareness in Eurobarometer surveys.  Here is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://rpubs.com/antaldaniel/734594&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;reproduction code&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;em&gt;intermediate to advanced R needed&lt;/em&gt;.) You should use the &lt;em&gt;development&lt;/em&gt; version of our &lt;a href=&#34;retroharmonize.dataobservatory.eu&#34;&gt;retroharmonize&lt;/a&gt; package at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/antaldaniel/retroharmonize&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;github.com/antaldaniel/retroharmonize&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are tracking changes in the boundaries of provinces, states, counties, parishes with our regions open source software &amp;ndash; &lt;a href=&#34;https://rpubs.com/antaldaniel/regions-OOD21&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;reproduction code here&lt;/a&gt;. You will need our &lt;a href=&#34;regions.dataobservatory.eu&#34;&gt;regions&lt;/a&gt; package which is available on CRAN or in the rOpenGov GitHub repo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will talk about how to join this with air pollution data and put it on the map with &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/post/2021-03-03-ood_interview_maps/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Milos Popovic&lt;/a&gt;, who prepared this nice choropleth animation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://reprex.nl/media/gif/eu_climate_change.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Milos Popovic&amp;amp;rsquo;s maps made from the case study.&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We will discuss data observatories (permanent data collection programs), open collaboration (open-source inspired way of cooperation among small and large independent actors) and data altruism.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any questions: send Daniel a message on &lt;a href=&#34;https://keybase.io/antaldaniel&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Keybase&lt;/a&gt;, Whatsapp or &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataandlyrics.com/#contact&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;email&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Hello on International &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/OpenDataDay2021?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#OpenDataDay2021&lt;/a&gt; from🌷 the Hague!&lt;br&gt;- We have brought some new data to the light about 🌡climate change awareness &lt;br&gt;- We created some tutorials how to harmonize survey and geographical data&lt;br&gt;- Join us at 9.30 EST/15.30 CET 👇&lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/7J7pvi3sPC&#34;&gt;https://t.co/7J7pvi3sPC&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/ODD2021?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#ODD2021&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/DwkGQaDhW1&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/DwkGQaDhW1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; dataandlyrics (@dataandlyrics) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dataandlyrics/status/1368149535436996609?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;March 6, 2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reprex introduction in IVIR</title>
      <link>https://reprex.nl/talk/reprex-introduction-in-ivir/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 10:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reprex.nl/talk/reprex-introduction-in-ivir/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;IViRtual 9 April 2021&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
